# Abhinav Gupta

#### Design @ Google

A multi-disciplinary designer with 9+ years of domain experience in designing and developing for enterprise and consumer grade applications to create meaningful and easy to use products. Extensive working knowledge of LLM's, agentic Al concepts, vibecoding and how they shape UX and the design process.

Mobile: +1 647-467-0393

Email: abhinav191@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/abhinav191

Website: www.itsabhi.com

#### Work experience

#### Sr. Interaction Designer @ Google Canada

October 2024 - Present

Toronto, Canada

Led the design for a completely new product SaaS Runtime from ground up,  $0 \rightarrow 1$ , being the sole designer handling multiple integrations with Google Cloud products and stakeholders, leading to successful preview in Google Cloud Next'25.

- Drove the design vision and execution for the App-centric SaaS Runtime platform, contributing to the overall product vision.
- Proactively engaged in defining complex requirements and product integrations while utilizing quant data to influence outcomes for the product.
- Improved and iterated on the onboarding flow of the product to increase adoption and data model rate by 50%
- Pioneered Al application in design workflows by building interactive prototypes helping save more than 80% time, which helped in alignment with stakeholders and moving the design vision forward quickly.
- Created guides and presented to wider UX design team on application of AI to improve design workflows.

#### Senior Product Designer @ Cresta Al

April 2024 - October 2024

Toronto, Canada

Worked and owned the design for the flagship no code Gen Al platform to make automated workflows helping contact center admins to track progress and provide coaching opportunities.

- Owned the end-to-end design process across AI Agent surfaces (chat, voice UIs) as well as the builder, training, and tooling ecosystem: research synthesis → interaction/IA → visual polish → production handoff and iteration.
- Reduced TTV for the users to train model by 25% by refining the RAG LLM's workflow.
- Cross functional alignment and partnership to define the future vision for the product and user testing it for validation and further iteration of the product.

## Interaction Designer @ Google UK

May 2022 - April 2024

London, UK

Worked on release tools(CI/CD) for Google to help rollout new versions and updates to apps like Youtube, Gmail, Workspace etc to consumers all around the world

- Improved the UX of the tool and updated it to the latest design standards, resulting in increased in EngSat score by 50%.
- Introduced and kicked off the accessibility audit of the product and worked in close collaboration with engineering to make the product a11y compliant by 100%.
- Ongoing technical collaborations with engineers and dta scientists to define product workflows

### Product Designer @ VMware

Nov 2019 - April 2022

India

Designed for the flagship product VMware vRealize Automation - a powerful and easy-to-use Infrastructure Automation Platform. Worked as the only designer from India for the team driving forward the initiative for providing a consumer grade experience to our users.

### UX Designer @ SAP

July 2017 - Oct 2019

India

Worked as the Lead Designer from Bangalore-India location to create unified experiences for the internal tools development team. Extensive collaboration with Design teams, Product Managers and Developers from global locations for user research, testing, design reviews and driving local and global projects forward.

### Sr. UI Engineer @ Group10

Oct 2012 - June 2015

India

Worked with front-end technologies like HTML,CSS and Javascript and frameworks like Drupal with mobile platform development in Android to make websites and mobile applications.

### Skills

Design: UX design, Interaction design, Generative AI, User research, Usability testing, UI design, Information architecture, Motion design, Graphic design, Data visualization

Tools: Figma, Cursor, Windsurf, Al Studio, Sketch, Framer, Principle, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe After Effects, Adobe InDesign

**Technology:** HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap, Bulma, Git,

#### Education

2015 - 2017

Master of Design at National Institute of Design, India

2008 - 2012

Bachelor of Technology at Indraprasth University, India